Guide to the American Demographics records, 1979-2004.
American Demographics records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
American Demographics records, 1979-2004.
6794
2 cubic feet.
Printed material
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection consists of records related to the publication of American Demographics. Includes reports, clippings, oral history recordings, and memorabilia.
American Demographics was a journal founded in Ithaca, New York by Peter Francese in 1979. The magazine focused on analysis of demographic data and its interpretation for planners and marketers. The journal was published until 2004, when it was acquired by Advertising Age, which incorporated the name and some content into its magazine.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection consists of records related to the publication of American Demographics. Includes reports, clippings, oral history recordings, and memorabilia.
SUBJECTS
Subjects:
Demography -- Periodicals.; Demographic surveys -- United States
Places:
United States -- Population -- Periodicals.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Local and American Demographics correspondence, marketing, and quotes, 1979 - 1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous correspondence, 1980 - 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- American Demographics six-year index, 1981 - 1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Clippings and quotes, 1979 - 1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Associated Press story, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Clippings and reports, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Newspaper clippings, 1985 - 1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Clippings and articles, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Newspaper clippings, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Five-year plan, 1988 - 1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Regions: Expanded - Notes for new section of magazine, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Newspaper clippings and reports, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Clippings and quotes, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Memos, 1988 - 1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Reader survey, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- J. Parsons, Art Production Director, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Blayne Cutler, Editor, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Newspaper clippings and reports, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Jerri Dougherty, Editorial Assistant, 1989 - 1990 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Dow Jones correspondence and reports, 1984 - 1990 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Business environment for Dow Jones in the 1980s, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Clippings and reports, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- The Marketer and competition, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- List of employees, 1987 - 1990 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Clippings and quotes, 1982 - 1995 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Miscellaneous memos, 1990 - 1991 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Media mentions, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- The Popcorn Report, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Survey of subscribers, ca. 1992 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Cliipings and Quotes, 1992 - 1993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- New magazine planning, Marketing Tools, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Focus groups, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Five-year plan, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Oral history interviews by Curt Freitag, 1978 - 1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Oral history transcripts (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Company history (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Library (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Wednesdays newsletter, 1986 - 1987 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Wednesdays newsletter, 1987 - 1990 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Rolodex cards(Brad Edmondson), 1990 - 1991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- American Demographics promotional eraser, MU-2050 (Box 2)
  Logo and slogan,"Because the Numbers Are Always Changing"
- Lucite obelisk, MU-2051 (Box 2)
  EDI award from National Easter Seal Society to Judith Waldrop for article "The Demographics of Disability"
- VHS tape - Tom Parker on The Tonight Show, October 16, 1987; V-6838 (Box 2)
  Tom Parker promoting his book of American Demographics covers called In One Day, with cover note from Peter A. Steen to Jill Charboneau.
- Cassette tape - American Demographics oral history: Peter Francese and Mary Riche, tr-9884 (Box 2)
- Cassette tape - American Demographics oral history: Penelope Wickham, Doris Walsh, and Cheryl Russell, tr-9885 (Box 2)
- Cassette tape - American Demographics oral history: Cally Arthur and Jill Charboneau, tr-9886 (Box 2)
- Cassette tape - American Demographics oral history: Ellen Marsh and Mike Rider, tr-9887 (Box 2)
- Cassette tape - American Demographics oral history: Nancy Ten Kate, Gail Butterfield, Michelle DeChant, and Bickley Townsend, tr-9888 (Box 2)
- Cassette tape - American Demographics oral history: Terri Robinson, Diane Crispell, tr-9889 (Box 2)
- Cassette tape - Brad Edmondson on the 1990 census, WAMR/WCTQ,Venice,Florida, October 9, 1988; tr-9890 (Box 2)
- Mergenhagen, Paula.Targeting Transitions: Marketing to Consumers During Life Changes, 1985 (Box 2)
- Braus, Patricia. Marketing Health Care to Women, 1997 (Box 2)
- Dunn, William.The Baby Bust: A Generation Comes of Age, 1992 (Box 2)
- Dunn, William. Selling the Story: The Layman's Guide to Collecting and Communicating Demographic Information, 1993 (Box 2)
- Waldrop, Judith with Marcia Mogelonsky. The Seasons of Business: The Marketer's Guide to Consumer Behavior, 1992 (Box 2)
- Francese, Peter. Capturing Customers: How to Target the Hottest Markets of the '90s, 1990 (Box 2)
- Cloth banner, 26" x 26", pre-1988; MU-1863 (Folder 1)
  Banner front has American Demographics pre-1988 logo on yellow backing and "A Dow Jones Company" in black letters underneath, back of banner has label "Clothworks, Ithaca, NY".